Guide to the Julie Schwartzberg Collection on the District Council 37 Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee WAG.366
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Julie Schwartzberg Collection on the District Council 37 Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee
1988-2000
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Schwartzberg, Julie
WAG.366
1 linear foot in 2 manuscript boxes
Julie Schwartzberg is a public health advisor, and a founding member and the first co-chair of District Council 37's Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee (LAGIC). She had previously served as the vice president of AFSCME Local 768. Through her general organizing work and involvement in LAGIC specifically, Schwartzberg worked to support LGBTQ union members by "increasing their visability, affirming their dignity, and promoting a non-homophobic workplace environment." The Julie Schwartzberg Collection on the District Council 37 Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee documents the founding and activities of American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37's Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee (LAGIC) to support LGBTQ union members. Materials in this collection include newsletters, correspondence, meeting minutes, notes, event flyers, and ephemera from LAGIC conferences. The collection documents LAGIC's early organizing work to be formally recognized by DC-37, community-building efforts, and network of coalition building, as well as Schwartzberg's appointment to the AFSCME Advisory Committee as a co-chair of LAGIC. The collection also includes files of general labor and other social justice issues about which members of LAGIC were interested, concerned, or working to support. The bulk of the collection documents LAGIC's early advocacy efforts to be formally recognized by DC-37. These materials include petitions, letters, flyers, agendas, meeting minutes, and speech drafts. LAGIC's community-building efforts and participation in national protests such as the 1993 March on Washington are also strongly documented in this collection. Event materials demonstrate LAGIC's intersectional approach to its organizing, and include flyers for events specific to celebrating the lives of Black and Latinx workers, and support for self-defense and support teams in response to a rash of violence against women in Park Slope, Brooklyn. Flyers, correspondence, budgets, and other planning materials document the various local committees' activities, including protests, social events, and local and national conferences specific to LGBTQ workers.
Scope and Contents
The Julie Schwartzberg Collection on the District Council 37 Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee (dated 1988-2000) documents the founding and activities of American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37's Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee (LAGIC) to support LGBTQ union members. Materials in this collection include newsletters, correspondence, meeting minutes, notes, event flyers, and ephemera from LAGIC conferences. The collection documents LAGIC's early organizing work to be formally recognized by DC-37, community-building efforts, and network of coalition building, as well as Schwartzberg's appointment to the AFSCME Advisory Committee as a co-chair of LAGIC. The collection also includes files of general labor and other social justice issues about which members of LAGIC were interested, concerned, or working to support. The bulk of the collection documents LAGIC's early advocacy efforts to be formally recognized by DC-37. These materials include petitions, letters, flyers, meeting agendas, meeting minutes, and speech drafts. LAGIC's community-building efforts and participation in national protests such as the 1993 March on Washington for Lesbian, Gay, and Bi Equal Rights and Liberation are also strongly documented in this collection. Event materials demonstrate LAGIC's intersectional approach to its organizing, and include flyers for events specific to celebrating the lives of Black and Latinx workers, and support for self-defense and support teams in response to a rash of violence against women in Park Slope, Brooklyn. Flyers, correspondence, budgets, and other planning materials document the various local committees' activities, including protests, social events, and local and national conferences specific to LGBTQ workers.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Julie Schwartzberg in June 2021; the accession number associated with this gift is 2021.031.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Appraisal
Sign-up sheets containing personally identifiable information were removed from the collection prior to acquisition.
Biographical Note
Julie Schwartzberg is a public health advisor, and a founding member and the first co-chair of District Council 37's Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee (LAGIC). She had previously served as the vice president of AFSCME Local 768. Through her general organizing work and involvement in LAGIC specifically, Schwartzberg worked to support LGBTQ union members by "increasing their visability, affirming their dignity, and promoting a non-homophobic workplace environment" (DC37.net/about/committees/lagic).
Source:
District Council 37. "DC 37: Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee." https://www.dc37.net/about/committees/lagic (retrieved July 6, 2021).
Activism (LGBTQ); Discrimination (LGBTQ); Labor movement -- New York (N.Y.); Labor unions; Labor unions -- Organizing -- New York (N.Y.); Labor unions -- Political activity; Civil service -- New York (N.Y.); Municipal officials and employees -- New York (N.Y.); Civil rights (LGBTQ); Schwartzberg, Julie; AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.); AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.). Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee
- Newsletters and Brochure, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Newspaper, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Dykes and Tykes, circa 1988-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Pre-Recognition and Early Organizing Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Meeting Minutes, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Organizing and Recognition, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Committee Meeting Agendas, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Advisory Commitee, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Treasurer, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Advisory Committee, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- AFL-CIO, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- General Labor, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- AFSCME Resolutions, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 1993 March on Washington (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Local 768 LAGIC, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- LAGIC -- General, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- DC 37 Pride Events, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Pride Dinner Dance, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Hispanic Heritage Celebration, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- New York State Legislation, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Pride Budgets, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Resignation Letter, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Events, 1989-1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Flyers, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Meetings at DC 37 and Center, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Events, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Local 768, 1989-1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Pride Agenda Conference, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Pride Agenda Conference Articles, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Lesbian and Gay Labor Network (LGLN), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Conferences, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- General Labor Issues, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
- Newsclippings, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Domestic Partnership, 1989-1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Discrimination, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- AIDS, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Newsletters and Conferences, 1992-2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Pre-Recognition Organizing and The Center, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- General LGBTQ, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Poster, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Pride at Work Organizing Booklet, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Out at Work Film, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Activities, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Labor Conferences, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)